(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T02:47:34.958643",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
始まりはきっと
The beginning was surely
一つの願い
a single wish.
それを抱いて
Embracing that,
私は
I was...
生まれた
born.
孤独な夜空
In the lonely night sky,
震える両手で
with trembling hands,
点と点を繋げよう
let's connect the dots.
一次元では
In one dimension,
寂しすぎるから
it was too lonely,
私たちは
so we...
広がりを求めた
sought expansion.
点は線となり
Points became lines,
線は立体となり
lines became 3D shapes,
そこに距離が生まれたけれど
and distance was born there, but...
三次元では
In three dimensions,
ちょっと遠すぎるから
it's a bit too far,
私たちは
so we...
平面にも求めた
sought a 2D plane as well.
点は線となり
Points became lines,
線は星座となり
lines became constellations,
この夜空をつなぐよ
connecting this night sky.
自分らしく
A place where...
いられる場所を
I can be myself...
気づけばずっと探していた
When I realized it, I was searching all along.
煌めく星よ
O glittering stars,
たどり着く先で
at the place we arrive,
この旗を
holding this flag...
目印に
as our landmark,
あの日君がいつも
because on that day you were always...
そこにいたから
there,
嬉しくて続けられたんだ
I was happy and able to keep going.
今日まで忘れないでね
Don't forget up until today.
僕らの星座は
Our constellation...
君がいたから生まれた
was born because you were here.
たとえ君がいつの時代を生きてても
Even if you live in whatever era,
何かを好きになる気持ち
the feeling of coming to love something,
大切に歌い続けてね
please keep singing with care.
僕らの星座は
Our constellation...
君がいるから生まれ
was born because you are here,
夜空に輝き
shining in the night sky,
明日へと繋がる
and connects to tomorrow.
未来を
Towards the future...
目指すよ
we aim...
共に進もう
let's go forward together.
これは僕らのキセキ。
僕とキミと、大切なあの子の。
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る僕たちの物語。
小説『FBKINGDOM STORY』ED1冒頭抜粋
[This is our miracle.
Mine, yours, and that precious girl's.
Our story, chronicling the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom.
Novel "FBKINGDOM STORY" ED1 Opening Excerpt]
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where is the meaning of my existence?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't completely abandon my dreams and hopes, but...
なんとなく今を生きている
I'm somehow living in the present.
あー どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
あー どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
I caught the scent of fragrant olive,
明日のことも忘れたくなった
and felt like forgetting about tomorrow too.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away,
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I am the protagonist of a tragedy.
やさしいヒトで居たいな
I want to remain a kind person,
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
but even feelings like that are hypocrisy.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy,
都合良いね、涙が出るの
how convenient, tears start falling.
あー どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
あー どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
あー 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe.
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
Someday, even this song will come to an end.
あー 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe.
この地球もいつかは終わりが来る
Someday, even this world will come to an end.
金木犀の匂いをまた
Once again, the scent of fragrant olive
思い出した
came back to my mind.
気付けば... 駆けだしていた...
Before I knew it... I was running...
揺れ動く... 心のままに...
following my swaying heart...
遠ざかる... 白い壁...
The white walls... recede into the distance...
一度も... 振り返らずに...
without turning back... even once...
《生命》が... 消えゆく季節の...
In the season when life fades away...
胸を刺す... 気配の中で...
amidst a presence that pierces my heart...
迫りくる... 暗い闇...
The dark shadows... approaching...
二度と... 明けないような気がして...
feeling as though dawn will never come again...
転がり落ちそうな心...
My heart, feeling on the verge of tumbling down...
必死に抱きとめていた...
I desperately held on to it...
星空へと続く長い坂道は...
Because the long hill leading to the starry sky...
永遠にも... 思えたから...
felt like it went on forever...
咲く花や... 散りぬるを...
Flowers bloom and scatter...
神代の《時代》より繰り返す...
repeating ever since the age of gods...
私はそれを... 美しいとは... 思ったことがない...
I have never once thought of that... as beautiful...
久方の... 春の陽を...
The spring sun in the distant sky...
仮初めの影が奪い合う...
transient shadows fight over it...
その営みを... 美しいとは... 思ったことがない...
I have never once thought of that struggle... as beautiful...
諦めながら... 生きてた...
I lived on... giving up...
何も望まないように...
as if wishing for nothing at all...
それでも...
Even so...
手放せなかった... 最後の願ひを...
I could not let go... of my final wish...
握りしめて... 駆け上がる
Clenching it tight... I run up the hill.
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
When you, living so recklessly and earnest, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴が得をする世界で
in a world where those who live easily take all the profit,
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I, at least, will never laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
ああ人は滅んでゆく 蝕んでゆく
Ah, humanity perishes, corroding away,
才を妬み合い 富を奪い合い
envying each other's talents, stealing each other's wealth,
ああ人は滅んでゆく 蝕んでゆく
Ah, humanity perishes, corroding away,
その果てに見えた海は 地獄だろうか？それとも地獄だろうか？
Is the sea seen at the end hell? Or is it hell after all?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
When you, living so recklessly and earnest, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴が得をする世界で
in a world where those who live easily take all the profit,
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I, at least, will never laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも 我は笑わない！
No matter if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
Even if you, living honestly, are looked down upon,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも 我は離さない！
Even as time ticks on and forgets, I will not let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if you work yourself to the bone,
感謝されないことも……（シノシノ）
And aren't appreciated either...
「自己犠牲」を受け入れられても 限界がもうやってくるから
Even if you accept "self-sacrifice", your limits will eventually catch up,
自分を大事に愛せばいい
So just treasure and love yourself.
それは他人を愛すること
That is what it means to love others.
ああ人は滅んでゆく 縺れてゆく
Ah, people perish, becoming entangled,
元に戻ってゆく
Returning to how they were.
ああ人は泣いてゆく 救われてゆく
Ah, people cry, and are saved,
君に逢えたから…… 君を愛したから……
Because I met you... Because I loved you...
君が闘うなら…… 僕も闘うから……
If you fight... I will fight too...
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
Even if you, living recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who take the easy way out benefit,
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも 我は笑わない！
No matter if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
Even if you, living honestly, are looked down upon,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies prosper,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも 我は離さない！
Even as time ticks on and forgets, I will not let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
それじゃぁ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight, let me tell you a story about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
Truth or lie, the book written here is a mysterious one whose contents constantly change.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now then, I wonder what kind of story it has become this time.
これはあるサーカスの一団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story about a circus troupe visiting the kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが綺羅びやかなステージに包まれたお話。
and a still-inexperienced ringmaster surrounded by a dazzling stage.
あぁ……これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング……！
Ah... This is the dream ending I wished for...!
さあ、今日も始まりました〜！
Now, today's show has begun~!
煌びやか、享楽のパレード
A dazzling, pleasure-filled parade!
常識もここじゃ無関係
Common sense doesn't matter here!
踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Dance, sing, make noise, and forget everything!
細かいことは置いていいて
Put aside the fine details,
とりあえず身を任せてみな
For now, just surrender yourself to the groove!
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴
A banquet to share a little bit of happiness,
Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
Piling anxieties and regrets,
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
Turn your eyes away just for now!
そのままじゃ楽しめないジャン この場だけは何もかも忘れて！
You can't enjoy it like that, right? Forget everything just in this place!
幾千の価値観全部
Thousands of values and views,
引っ括め楽しませたげる！
I'll wrap them all together and make you enjoy it!
百鬼夜行もビックリの隊を成している
Formed into a procession that would even shock the Night Parade!
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
A comedy mimicking the bizarre raises its curtain,
一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
Take one look and you'll instantly be captivated!?
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる
Accepting any kind of love,
ここだけはあなたの理想郷
This place alone is your utopia!
「もう間もなく主役の登場、
"The star will be appearing shortly,
一時でも目を離さないで！」
Don't take your eyes off for even a moment!"
眩いほどのステージが始まる。
A stage so dazzling begins.
華々しいスポットライトの中
In the middle of the brilliant spotlights,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
A multitude of eye-catching, amazing tricks!
この空間が世界で一番
This space is in the world the most
“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
Worthy of the name "Entertainment"!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With thunderous cheers and applause,
ショーが終わっていく
The show comes to an end...
↑まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが^^;
↑Well, this is purely an ideal story though ^^;
さて、今日も始めましょうか…
Now then, shall we begin today's performance?
あ〜；；またやっちゃった
Ahhh... I messed up again!
実際はご覧の通り、まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです；；
In reality, as you can see, I'm still just an inexperienced apprentice...
先人に憧れ持って 私も！と飛び込んだものの
Admiring my predecessors, I jumped right in thinking "Me too!",
現実 はそんな簡単に 上手くいかないな
but reality isn't going that smoothly...
もう一回！
One more time!
「怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？」
"A bizarre comedy begins! Fall under its spell at first sight!?"
え？ 既にそれさっき見た？
Huh? You already saw that a moment ago?
なら、飽き性なあなたにも【朗報】
Well then, good news for those of you who get bored easily!
Q. ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ？
Q. Are you just copying what was done before?
A. 繰り返しじゃつまらない！
A. Repetition is boring!
だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
So from here on out, let's change things up!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は
Where this hectic circus is headed...
誰にも自分すらも分からない！？
Nobody knows, not even ourselves!?
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ〜〜〜！！！
Since you chose me, at least you have a great time!
損させない
I won't let you down!
いつの日か皆と楽しめるショーがしたいんだよな
Someday, I want to put on a show everyone can enjoy together!
だからこそ、こんなとこで挫けるわけとかな〜い！
That's why there's no way I'm giving up here!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない あの感動を私もいつか…
Someday, I want to create that emotion that words can't describe...
とても偉大なこのステージに見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know if I'm worthy of this grand stage,
観客すべて、私の色で 染め尽くしてやろう！
but I'll paint every single audience member in my colors!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ〜〜〜！！！
Starting right now with all of you right in front of me!
創造
Create!
華々しいスポットライトの中
Inside the brilliant spotlight,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
a series of captivating, dazzling tricks!
この空間が世界で一番“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space deserves the title of "entertainment" more than anywhere in the world!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で ショーが終わっていく
Amidst thunderous cheers and applause, the show comes to a close...
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング
Ah... this is the dream ending I've always wanted!
これは 花の国のお姫様が この王国へいらっしゃった時のお話
This is the story of when the princess of the Flower Kingdom visited this realm.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので 国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど、
Since no one knew her well back then, most citizens called her a silly girl,
とっても心優しくそして気さくで頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ
but she was actually a kindhearted, friendly, and reliable princess.
なんたって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！ 聖女！ 叡智！ 聡明！ 慈愛！ 博愛！ ですわ！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Brilliance! Compassion! Philanthropy! Indeed!
あたしなんたったってお姫様
After all, I'm a princess!
この人生におけるヒロイン ですわー！
I'm the heroine of this life, indeed!
一生平穏でイージーモード！
Easy mode with a peaceful life forever!
って思ったら勝手にどうぞ？ 世間はいつも風向き次第！
If you think so, suit yourself! The world changes like the wind!
有象無象ばかりでホント
It's truly full of ordinary riff-raff!
人間不信になっちゃう！
I'm losing faith in humanity!
気づいたのこの世界に 血も涙もないこと
I realized that this world has neither blood nor tears.
あれもダメ これもダメ それもダメ どれもダメ
That's no good, this is no good, that's no good, none of it is good!
現実世知辛い 全部改変ですわ…！
Reality is harsh, so I'm rewriting it all!
あたしなんたったってお姫様 この人生におけるヒロイン
After all, I'm a princess! The heroine of this life!
悲しいシナリオも 全部全部書き換えちゃうの
Even sad scenarios, I'll rewrite them all!
だってだってお姫様 自分の物語くらいは
After all, I'm a princess! At least my own story...
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I have to enjoy it sparkle and shine! Yes indeed!
今にみてなさい！ 運命なんて改変して差し上げますわ！
Just you wait! I'll rewrite fate itself for you!
だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ だれ？ 裏で糸を引いてるのは誰？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? Who is pulling the strings behind the scenes?
操り人形だなんてごめんだわ まったく
Being a puppet? No thank you, seriously!
上品な顔してても 黒幕はあの人かも
Even with that refined face, that person might be the mastermind!
まずはあたしが 強くならなきゃ 未来は変わらない
First, I have to become stronger, or the future won't change!
改革だ… 自分改革ですわ…！
Time for reform... A self-reform, indeed!
そうよなんたったってお姫様 あたしこそ最高権力者
That's right, after all I'm a princess! I am the supreme authority!
生涯のすべての主導権はこちらにあるわ
All initiative in my life belongs right here to me!
だってだってお姫様 自分で決めたことくらいは
After all, I'm a princess! At least the things I decided for myself...
わがままに行かなきゃ
I have to do whatever I want!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
女神！聖女！叡智！聡明！慈愛！博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Brilliance! Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Desu wa!
今日も軽くステップして
Lightly stepping today as well,
運命の歯車が踊り出す
the gears of fate begin to dance.
顔を上げたその時 ほら世界が恋する
The moment you look up, see, the whole world falls in love!
あたし ハッピーエンドプリンセス この人生におけるヒロイン
I am a happy end princess, the heroine of this life!
すったもんだある日々も 全部全部 愛してみせるの
Even through chaotic days, I'll love every single bit of it!
ハッピーエンドプリンセス 自分の物語くらいは
Happy end princess! At least in my own story,
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I've gotta sparkle and enjoy it!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ
I've gotta live life to the fullest!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
今にみてなさい！
Just you watch!
運命なんて 改変して差し上げますわ！
I shall rewrite something like fate for you!
女神！聖女！叡智！聡明！慈愛！博愛！ですわ！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Brilliance! Affection! Philanthropy! Desu wa!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の1つじゃないか
Isn't this one of the novels that became famous overnight in the kingdom?
…ある女子学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい…え？
...A fun tale woven by a female student detective and a mystery writer... Huh?
いやいやこの事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ
No, no, I don't know if this case actually happened.
でも、このシリーズは凄く人気なんですよね
But this series is extremely popular, you know.
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I've got it! The culprit is you!
悪漢ベーカー ストリート雷雨
Villain, Baker Street, rainstorm.
七つ道具は質屋へ
Off to the pawnshop with the sleuthing tools.
悪路 井戸落とされ探偵が
Pushed down a well on a rough road, a detective...
また一人姿を消したといふ
...is said to have vanished once again.
綾なす辻のAlice側
On the Alice side of the woven crossroads,
横溝掃除は江戸川か
Is cleaning out the side gutters a job for Edogawa?
神田最弱探偵さん
The weakest detective of Kanda,
こんなんどう？居ると思う？
How about this? Do you think they exist?
ナンマンダブ ステップ踏み
Chanting prayers while stepping around,
脳髄是密室なりや
Is the mind itself a locked room?
グーとチーで合った人
Those matched by rock and scissors,
愚と智で分かれましょう
Let's divide by foolishness and wisdom.
謎解きはこれから
The mystery solving starts now.
「犯人はあなたですね」
"The culprit is you, isn't it?"
列車トリック 発火トリック 難事件
Train tricks, ignition tricks, difficult cases.
推理作家の先生さん 阿破破
Mr. Mystery Writer, ahaha!
うーだらぱーだら うーだらぱーだら 言わないで
Don't go babbling non-stop nonsense!
あーもう 頭がこんがらかってきたけれど
Ah, geez, my head's getting all tangled up, but...
どっと払い どっと混む あっちゃっちゃっちゃっ パリパリ
Laughter erupts, crowds gather, hot hot crisp crisp!
海鷂魚鱇場でわんこそば
Wanko soba at the stingray and anglerfish arena!
「謎はおやつに入りません」
"Mysteries don't count as snacks!"
どっと払い どっと混む あっちゃっちゃっちゃっ どんしゃり どんしゃり
Laughter erupts, crowds gather, hot hot clatter clatter!
エブリバディ アリバイ ない ない ない
Everybody's alibi is nowhere to be found!
etc ライヘンバッハ 烏啼き
Etc., Reichenbach, crows cawing,
番台さん突いて御清聴
Tapping the counter, thank you for your attention!
織り笑むと旧校舎の窓
Smiling through woven lies, the old school building window,
あの怪盗達が待つといふ
...where those phantom thieves are said to await.
高木に二人 海野原
Two at Takagi, and Ocean Fields,
坂口暗号無視したろう
You probably ignored the Sakaguchi code, right?
ABCだか恵比寿だか
Whether it's ABC or Ebisu,
「檸檬どう？」 ちゃんとして
"How about a lemon?" Get your act together!
甲が乙を隠す
Party A hides Party B,
そんじゃ降参 鑑識さんお疲れさん
Well then I surrender, thanks for your hard work, forensics!
四捨五入やってみな
Try rounding to the nearest whole,
死者五人どこ行った
Where did the five dead bodies go?
謎解きはまだまだ
The mystery solving is far from over!
「そして誰がいなくなった？」
"And then, who vanished?"
およしになって おやめになって 怪事件
Please stop that, refrain from that, mysterious cases!
おさげ揺らす探偵さん 『探偵さん』
Pigtail-swaying detective, "Detective!"
ノックスべべ ガストンべべ 行かないで
Knox baby, Gaston baby, don't go!
and more 作者のギワル毎度
And more, the author's usual mischief!
どっと払い どっと混む あっちゃっちゃっちゃっ パリパリ
Laughter erupts, crowds gather, hot hot crisp crisp!
エブリバディ わんこそば
Everybody, wanko soba!
「たまには自分で考えたまえ」
"Think for yourself once in a while!"
どっと払い どっと混む あっちゃっちゃっちゃっ どんしゃり どんしゃり
Laughter erupts, crowds gather, hot hot clatter clatter!
エブリバディ アリバイ ない ない ない
Everybody, alibi: none, none, none!
怪盗連盟の罠にはまり
Trapped by the League of Phantom Thieves,
次々と姿を消していく名探偵たち
great detectives vanish one after another.
そして探偵の居ぬ間に
And in the absence of detectives,
人々の心は密室となった
people's hearts became locked rooms.
「でも、それならどうしておあたしだけが無事だったんでしょうか？」
"But if so, why was I the only one who remained safe?"
「その答えはひとつしか考えられない」
"There can be only one answer to that."
「と、言うと……？」
"Which is...?"
「あまりにも無能すぎるがゆえに、君は探偵として勘定にも入れられていなかったのだ！」
"Because you're so utterly incompetent, you weren't even considered a detective!"
「ひーっ！？」
"Eeeek?!"
お屋敷になって おやめになって 怪事件
Becoming a mansion, stop it, a mysterious case.
お下げ揺らす 探偵さん
Detective with swinging pigtails...
ノックス ヴァンダイン 行かないで
Knox, Van Dine, please don't go!
ああもう 探偵の いじわる いけず
Ah, enough, detective, you're mean and cold!
列車トリック 発火トリック 難事件
Train trick, fire-starting trick, a difficult case.
推理作家の 先生
Mystery writer, Sensei!
うだだ パダダ 言わないで
Udada, padada, don't say that!
ああもう 頭が こんがらかってきたけれど
Ah, enough, my mind is getting all tangled up, but...
かわいかわいや
Oh, sweet and lovely...
トリック暴いて
Expose the trick!
通りゃんせ
You may pass through.
小さい2人の子供が約束した、ずっといっしょに笑っていようの約束
Two little children made a promise, a promise to laugh together forever.
今なお、二人の絆は確かなもので…友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語
Even now, their bond remains firm... A wonderful story woven of friendship and love.
あははっ …なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ
Ahaha... Sometimes you just get a giggling fit over the smallest things, right?
あー 恋に落ちたまゆら 開花止まらないや 何度も捲って 心をかし
Ah, falling in love for a moment, flowering won't stop, turning pages again and again, charming the heart.
泣いてばっかったの それがどうだ今や 腹よじるくらい笑う
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now, laughing till my stomach hurts.
ずっと一緒に笑う
We'll laugh together forever.
きみが持ってる 白い花に あたし見合わない かなしみになる
The white flower you hold doesn't suit me, bringing sadness.
無垢な恋とか 正しさとか 誰も教えてくれなかった
Innocent love, righteousness... No one ever taught me about them.
昨日会ったばっかで 今日もどこか会えたら なんて思う暮らし つつましくないよね
We just met yesterday, yet wishing to see you again today... What a modest life, isn't it?
全部許されたの びっくりしちゃってさ 涙あふれていたよ
Everything was forgiven, taking me by surprise... My tears were overflowing.
もう要になる花歌 透き通った空に 手を繋いでいった 夢のしるし
A humming melody becoming vital, in the clear sky, holding hands... A mark of a dream.
どんな前世だってさ 忘れたっていいんだ きみと笑えるなら
Whatever past life it was, it's fine to forget it, as long as I can laugh with you.
心が触れるたび 綺麗な音鳴る 目と目が合って くすぐったいね
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings, our eyes meet and it feels ticklish.
なんでもないこと 妙につぼるね
Smallest things oddly bring a smile to our faces.
全部教えてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for teaching me everything.
きみが持ってる 白い花を あたしの紅色と合わせたら
If I combine the white flower you hold with my crimson color...
霜が溶けては 愛が行く もう寒くないよ
As the frost melts, love moves forward... It's not cold anymore.
あー 恋に落ちたまゆら 開花止まらないや 何度も捲って 心をかし
Ah, falling in love for a moment, flowering won't stop, turning pages again and again, charming the heart.
泣いてばっかったの それがどうだ今や 腹よじるくらい笑う
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now, laughing till my stomach hurts.
ずっと一緒に笑って
Laughing together forever...
心をかし
Charming the heart.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Laughing together forever...
最後の日を笑う
Laughing on our final day.
これは、遠い遠い名も知らぬ世界で、
This is in a far, far away world with no name...
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
A story of a girl who was cast with a curse of death.
遠い遠い時の果て そこに住まう人は
Far, far away at the end of time, the people living there...
皆永遠の命をもつ世界での話
This is a story of a world where everyone possesses eternal life.
赤い実の成る木の下 La La Lu La 生まれながらに
Beneath the tree bearing red fruit, La La Lu La, from the moment she was born...
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
This is the story of a girl cursed with death.
色付いた街外れ 蒼く光る湖畔 赤い実のお菓子屋
On the colorful outskirts, by the blue-glowing lakeside, lies a red fruit sweet shop.
ちょっぴり寒くなった今日は妙に誇らしげ 自新作を売りに行く
Feeling a bit chilly today, yet strangely proud, she sets off to sell her latest creation.
待ってて 今度こそ美味しいんだから
"Just wait, because this time it's truly delicious!"
時計塔の見える市 驚いた 珍しく賑やかね
At the market overlooking the clock tower, she's surprised—how unusually bustling it is!
La La Lu La Lucky!! 物憂げな街の隅 ひとり
La La Lu La Lucky!! Alone in a melancholy corner of the town,
赤い実のパイどうですか 自新作なの
"How about a red fruit pie? It's my pride and joy!"
そんなのひとりも売れないさ 少女を見て蔑む人達
"Not a single one of those will sell," say the people looking down on the girl.
みんなと何も変わらないのに 美味しくできたのに
"Even though I'm no different from anyone else, even though I made them so tasty..."
今日も声は届かないのね
Today as well, my voice doesn't reach anyone, does it?
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if I've become completely invisible.
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so, everyone pretended not to notice.
何故なら少女は呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed.
死んだ世界で唯ひとり生きていた少女の話
The story of a girl who lived all alone in a dead world.
夜なべでアレンジパイと にっこりスマイル引っ提げ 少女はまだ諦めない
Working through the night on new pie recipes, armed with a bright smile, the girl still won't give up.
時計塔の針も空を指してお腹も鳴るそんな時
Just as the clock tower's hands point skyward and her stomach rumbles,
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す 甘い籠は落ちる
Suddenly someone bumps into the girl from behind, spilling her sweet basket.
お菓子を踏み行く人達 平気な顔してさ
People walk by, stepping over the sweets with nonchalant expressions.
惨めに拾い集める ふともうひとりの手が
As she miserably gathers them up, suddenly another pair of hands joins in.
とろとろのパイを徐に口に入れて「おいしいね」
Placing a messy pie into his mouth, he says, "It's delicious."
その声で心は溢れた
With those words, her heart overflowed.
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It was as if her outline had finally been drawn.
そうして彼は手を差し出した
And then, he reached his hand out to her.
何故なら少女に呪われているから
Because he was enchanted by the girl.
死んだ世界で唯ふたり生きていた遠い物語
A distant tale of two who lived together in a dead world.
街の人達は哀れむ 赤い実を食べて呪われた者を
The townspeople pity those cursed from eating the red fruit.
永遠に生きられずに死ぬのさ 嗚呼なんて可哀想な話
"They can't live forever, they will die! Ah, what a tragic story," they cry.
ふたりは笑う それでも笑う
Yet the two laugh, smiling through it all.
La La La とっても素敵な呪いね
La La La, what a wonderful curse it is.
例え明日死んでも『今』が確かで大切になるから
Because even if we die tomorrow, "now" becomes real and precious.
もう声は届かないのね
No voices can reach them anymore.
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if they've become completely invisible.
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so, everyone pretended not to notice.
何故なら世界が呪われているから
Because the world itself is cursed.
『永遠』の呪いは解かれていた
The curse of "eternity" was lifted.
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
It must seem as though the two of them were the ones who went mad.
そうしていつか笑うように眠る
And so, sleeping as if to smile someday,
何故ならふたりは放たれているから
because the two of us have been set free.
死んだ世界で唯ふたりだけが幸せだった
In a dead world, only the two of us were happy.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう、
Well then, let us wrap things up for today.
…そろそろ時間になりましたし
...It's about that time, after all.
…え？どこへ向かうのかって？
...Huh? Where am I heading, you ask?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Don't you know what day it is today?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween party in the Underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです、
It's a once-a-year festival enjoyed by both the dead and the living.
さぁ、一緒に向かいましょう、
Now, let's head over together!
でも、気を付けて、
But be careful.
パーティーとはいえ、死者が住まう冥界です、
Party or not, it's the Underworld where the dead dwell.
誰かの思念や死者たちによって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれませんが、
Strange things may happen due to someone's thoughts or the dead themselves,
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ…
but you must never pay too much heed to them...
それでは、参りましょう
Well then, let us go.
蒼炎
[Blue Flame]
誰かが言いました
Someone once said,
激しく燃えるものほど
"The more intensely something burns,
煌めく引き換えに
in exchange for its radiance,
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
the sooner it burns itself out completely."
数ある燭台に
Upon the numerous candlesticks,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
let us light whichever flame you like.
期待と裏腹に
Contrary to expectations,
燻ればお生憎様
if it smolders, then what a pity.
ランランランラン
La la la la,
右手には錆びた時計
a rusty clock in the right hand.
ランランランラン
La la la la,
左には油の筒
a can of oil in the left.
ランランランラン
La la la la,
蠟のドレスを着飾って さあ
adorned in a dress of wax, come now.
激しく 儚く
Intensely, fleetingly,
蒼く燃ゆる花びら
blue burning petals.
瞬き ゆらめく
Flickering and swaying,
生を彩り照らせ
illuminate and color life,
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
toward a future that will eventually burn out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
Right before the cradle,
遙く飛び交う銃弾
bullets fly back and forth far away.
指だけ動かせば容易くその火は潰える
With just a move of a finger, that flame easily dies out.
仮初めの情熱で焼け爛れた舌では
With a tongue scorched by temporary passion,
上手に喋ることができないようで
it seems unable to speak properly.
喉元すぎても毒を孕ませて
Even after passing down the throat, harbored in poison,
やがては 肺を腐らせる
eventually rotting the lungs.
やがては肺を腐らせるでしょう
Eventually, it will rot your lungs.
ランランランラン 揺らぐ死と生の狭間
Swaying between life and death,
ランランランラン 焼ける心と歌う
I sing with a burning heart.
ランランランラン 描いた最愛の終幕を
Praising the beloved finale I envisioned.
激しく 儚く 蒼く燃ゆる花びら
Fiercely and fleetingly, blue burning petals...
瞬き ゆらめく 生を彩り照らせ
Flickering and wavering, illuminate and color life.
いずれ尽き果てるその先へ
Towards what lies beyond eventual exhaustion.
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
Before we get dragged into that world, we must hurry to the venue.
気をつけてついてきてくださいね、
Please follow carefully,
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
if you pry too deep, oops...
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ
That's right, it's probably wiser not to know.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね
Somehow, it feels really comfortable, doesn't it?
気づけば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unfamiliar world.
何処かも分からず 毎日 毎日 毎日 泣いていた
Without knowing where I was, I cried day after day.
なんて暇もなく
Without even time for that...
Happy Time! おかしな面々が
Happy Time! Strange faces...
Happy Time! おどけて転がるの
Happy Time! fooling around and tumbling.
Happy Time! その馬鹿馬鹿しさに 希望も恐怖もなくなった
Happy Time! In that absurdity, both hope and fear vanished.
確かそうアタシには 為すべき仕事 愛の棲家 パンプキン ヘッドギア
To be sure, I had work to do, a home of love, pumpkin headgear...
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow, none of it really matters.
さぁ始まった 夢の夜だ 音楽が響いて 鳴り止まない 声を揃えて 叫べ今日は
Now it's begun, a night of dreams! Music echoes without stopping! Raise your voices and shout today!
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ 真面目に生きても 割に合わない なんでもありさ 何故って今日は
Jack, tricks, anything goes! Living seriously isn't worth it, anything goes, because today is...
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
消えちゃった！ 消えちゃった！ 出口はないんだって そう 永遠に
Gone! Gone! They say there's no exit, yes, forever!
消えちゃった！ 消えちゃった！ 思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
Gone! Gone! Ideology, rules, ethics—none of it matters!
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
「私はロボットではありません」に
To 'I am not a robot',
無心でチェックし解答するけれど 本当にそうかな
I mindlessly check and answer, but is that really true?
Happy Life! とりま音に乗せて
Happy Life! For now, ride the sound,
Happy Life! デタラメに踊るの
Happy Life! dance randomly.
Happy Life! その繰り返しの中 懐疑心もしなった
Happy Life! In that repetition, even doubt withered away.
意思のない様 まるで ロボトミーした電気羊
Devoid of intention, just like a lobotomized electric sheep.
ナイトメア NPC
Nightmare NPC,
だけどなんか心地が良い
but somehow, it feels good.
What?
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio got distorted.
お気にになさらずに皆々様
Don't mind it, everyone.
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Sew those mouths shut,
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
Chocolate and candy for good kids' mouths,
歯に衣着せてっちゃ 噛み合わない
mincing words won't mesh well.
気を取り直し みんなでどうぞ
Pull yourselves together, everyone, please,
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
知っちゃった！ 知っちゃった！ 知っちゃった！ 知っちゃった！ 知っちゃった！ 知っちゃった！
I found out! I found out! I found out! I found out! I found out! I found out!
全部 全部 理解した
I understood everything, everything.
だから何も見たくねぇわ
So I don't wanna see anything at all.
さぁ始まった 夢の夜だ 音楽が響いて 鳴り止まない 声を揃えて 叫べ今日は
Now it's begun, a night of dreams! Music echoes without stopping! Raise your voices and shout today!
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ 真面目に生きても 割に合わない なんでもありさ 何故って今日は
Jack, tricks, anything goes! Living seriously isn't worth it, anything goes, because today is...
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
泣いちゃった！ 泣いちゃった！ 知らない方がきっと懸命ね
Cried! Cried! It's surely wiser not to know!
泣いちゃった！ 泣いちゃった！ このパーティーに終わりはない
Cried! Cried! There is no end to this party!
AMAZING HAPPY HALLOWEEN NIGHT
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
お菓子をくれても
Even if you give us treats...
イタズラはしちゃうよ！
...we're still gonna play tricks on you!
ようこそ everyone
Welcome everyone
身の毛もよだつこの spooky night
To this hair-raising spooky night
腹の底まで浸れ
Soak in deep to your core
kick & bass & hats & trumpet
ランタンと swingin' beat
Lanterns and a swingin' beat
赤い靴で踊り狂えば
If you dance like mad in red shoes,
浮世の憂いも忘れられるでしょ
you can forget the woes of this fleeting world, right?
近頃巷じゃ オバケよりも怖い人たち
Lately around town, people are scarier than ghosts
増えすぎっちゃってすぐに
They've increased so much, and right away...
1 out, 2 out, 3 out, KO!!
コンプライアンスも厳しい目の世の中ですが
Even in a world strict about compliance,
恐怖のリライト請け負います
we'll undertake the rewriting of terror.
GIVE ME A CHERRY PIE それとも may I choke you up?
GIVE ME A CHERRY PIE, or may I choke you up?
GIVE ME A FLOWY DRESS それとも may I stab you to death?
GIVE ME A FLOWY DRESS, or may I stab you to death?
poison, rope, pumpkin cake, knife, scissors, raspberry flake
choose one...
『さぁ選んで』
"Now, make your choice."
なんちって ドッキリ大成功！
Just kidding, total prank success!
響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
With resounding fanfares blasting,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいピース
smile brightly and say cheese!
あー怖かったななんて
Saying "Ah, that was scary,"
座り込んで涙目で
slumping down with teary eyes...
笑う顔見たいな
I wanna see your smiling face!
ちっちゃな箱の中の モンスターに怯えるくらいなら
If you're scared of monsters inside a tiny box,
いつだってここにおいで
come over here anytime.
もっとずっと本能的で楽しくなれる
You can have way more instinctive fun.
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with terror!
躁鬱相転移でキマってカタシス
Hitting that manic-depressive shift, pure catharsis!
もういっちょ感情ジェットコースターでゴキゲンデトックス
One more time on the emotional rollercoaster, happy detox!
満月が暴く醜悪な本性
The full moon reveals ugly true natures.
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
Randomly waving a wand, hocus pocus!
劣等感を苗床に育つ呪いを
The curse that grows with inferiority as its seed bed—
摘み取る術を知ってるかい？
do you know how to pluck it away?
『迷える哀れな子羊たちよ』
"O pitiless lost lambs,"
『お菓子が欲しいかい？ それともヤラレタキが欲しいかい？』
"do you want sweets? Or do you want a beating?"
『永遠に求め続けるの？』
"Will you keep seeking forever?"
『それならば、ずっと苦しいままだ』
"If so, you will suffer forever."
『恐怖からの解放によって』
"Through liberation from fear,"
『成し得る救いがあるのならば』
"if there is salvation to be gained,"
『この目隠しはそのままでに』
"keep this blindfold just as it is."
『さぁ、イタズラ完了』
"Now, prank complete."
永遠に断ち切れない
Bound by a curse's potion...
呪いのクスイに囚われ
...that can never be severed for eternity,
朽ち果ててしまう前に
before rotting away completely...
脳みそちょっと弄るだけであら不思議！
Just messing with your brain a bit, and oh how wondrous!
こんなに気持ち良くて気分爽快
It feels so good and refreshing!
なんちって ドッキリ大成功！
Just kidding, total prank success!
響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
With resounding fanfares blasting,
にっこり笑っちゃってはいポーズ
smile brightly and strike a pose!
あー辛かったななんて
Saying "Ah, that was tough,"
へたり込んで涙目で
collapsing down with teary eyes...
笑う顔っていいな
A smiling face is so nice!
もう苦しまなくていいよ こんなに頑張ったんだから
You don't have to suffer anymore, after trying so hard.
ためらわずこっちにおいで
Come over here without hesitation.
もうずっと本能的に気持ちいいだけの
I'll show you the goal where it just feels...
ゴールを見せてあげる
...instinctively good forever.
困窮極まってこそ光るカタシス
Catharsis shines brightest when hardship reaches its peak!
もういっちょ因果ぜリセットでタマシイデトックス
One more time, reset all karma for a soul detox!
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までも、
Even events of a world that might have existed someday...
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね。
...drift as thoughts like this here in the underworld.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ、こういうのが一番たちが悪い
You shouldn't dig too deep; these kinds are the worst of all.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ
I was simply loving you...
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Infusing vitality into these silent lips,
今宵「あなた」は甦る。
tonight, "you" are revived...
あの頃の姿で。
...in your form from back then.
白肌の娘が咳をした。
The fair-skinned girl coughed.
「この身体貴方に捧げるわ」
"I offer this body to you."
白服の医者が囁いた。
The doctor in white whispered,
「迎えに行くよ」
"I will come for you."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた。
The fair-skinned girl decayed,
世界の誰にも見捨てられ、
abandoned by everyone in the world.
白服の医者は憐れんで、
Pitied by the doctor in white,
誰も知らない居場所で眠らせた。
he laid her to rest where no one knew.
朽ちてもまだ
Though decayed, still...
美しい顔で、
...with a beautiful face,
ふたりしかない霊廟で、
in a mausoleum built for only two,
医者は恋をした。
the doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Is it eternal love?
禁断の行為か。
Or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
Just wishing to see you again...
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Is that really a sin?
物謂わぬ唇に
Into her silent lips,
生気を吹き込んで、
breathing life into them,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。
tonight, the two are united,
祝福もされずに。
without a single blessing.
『腐り落ちた眼孔に青い硝子を』
"Blue glass for the decayed eye sockets,"
『破れかけた腕に絹の肌を』
"silk skin for the torn arms,"
『侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを』
"cotton gauze for the diseased organs,"
『宝石で飾った白いドレスを』
"and a pure white dress adorned with jewels."
朽ちゆくたび
Every time she decayed,
取り繕って、
he patched her up,
恋を騙って、また医者は
falsely claiming it as love, the doctor
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは
Eventually, what was exposed
醜い怪物で、
was a hideous monster,
「それ」を作り上げた医者は
and the doctor who created "it"
弁駁を叫んだ。
shouted his defense:
「これは永遠の恋だ。
"This is eternal love.
彼女の願望だ。」
It was her wish."
死に行くと決めたお前らが
"Wasn't she the woman you abandoned,
見棄てた女じゃないか
deciding to leave her to die?"
嗚呼……哀しき花嫁。
Ah, sorrowful bride...
物謂えぬままで、
Remaining unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
tonight the two are judged
彼女を見棄てた人達の正義で。
by the justice of those who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is truly in the right?
さて、ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ。
Now, the Halloween party is finally coming to its finale.
ここで、ご参加くださった国民の皆様へ冥界からの「お土産品」のご紹介です！
Here, for all the citizens who participated, we introduce souvenir items from the underworld!
お土産品は、全4種類。
There are 4 types of souvenir items in total.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には、特典もございます。
Those who purchase the full set will also receive special bonus items.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう！
Let's take a closer look together!
まず1つ目、今回の「冥界ハロウィンナイト」をイメージした、ワイドラバーマットです。
First, here is the wide rubber mat inspired by this Underworld Halloween Night!
国王様の横には、冥界の女王の姿が。名を「ナイラ」というそうです。
Beside the King is the figure of the Underworld Queen, whose name is said to be Naira.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいという気持ちを込めた彼女のイメージソングも、この後お披露目予定なので、お楽しみに！
Her image song, filled with the wish for everyone to fully enjoy Underworld Halloween, will be revealed shortly, so please look forward to it!
素敵なイラストは、Matcha様に描いていただきました。
This lovely illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama!
2つ目は、パスポート風FBKINGDOMシール帳です。
Second, we have the passport-style FBKINGDOM sticker book!
このシール帳には、これからたくさんの思い出を記していきたいですね。
We hope to record many wonderful memories in this sticker book going forward.
王国の軌跡として、国民の皆様も今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか？
Why not collect stickers as a trace of our Kingdom's journey from now on, everyone?
その一歩として、今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを1枚封入しております。
As a first step, a sticker of this key visual is included inside!
3つ目は、SUKONBU FACTORYより、キングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです。
Third, from SUKONBU FACTORY, we have the King Fubu-chan plushie!
こちらは、国王自らデザインをしており、とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This was designed by the King herself, making it an extremely adorable plushie.
前回のVol.1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は、ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね。
If you have the previous Vol. 1 plushie, please display them together!
4つ目は、王国リボンチャームです。
Fourth is the Kingdom Ribbon Charm!
こちらは、司書である私の胸元のリボンが再現されております。
This reproduces the ribbon worn at the chest by me, the librarian.
ペンライトに付けるもよしと
You can attach it to a penlight,
多機能なリボンチャームとなっておりますので
making it a multi-functional ribbon charm,
皆様の「推し活」とやらに、ぜひご活用ください！
so please feel free to use it for your "oshi activities" or whatever you call it!
最後は特典のお知らせです
Lastly, here's an announcement regarding bonuses!
フルセットご購入の方全員に、チェキ風ブロマイドカードを1つお付けいたします
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive one Instax-style bromide card.
複製サインと、国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ
It also includes a printed autograph and a message from the King!
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン入りですので、皆様お早めに！
The limited-quantity version has a real handwritten signature, so get yours quickly!
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした！
That concludes our souvenir showcase for today!
さて
Now then,
この後は冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲
up next is a song inspired by the Queen of the Underworld,
『冥界Halloween Night!』のお披露目です
the unveiling of "Underworld Halloween Night!"
楽し創された後は
After you've enjoyed yourselves,
無事 王国へお帰りくださいね
please return safely to the Kingdom, okay?
それでは！
Here we go!
Welcome!
さあ、踊ろうよ
Come on, let's dance!
This is Halloween Night!
冥界を挙げての Party (Party)
A party hosted by the entire Underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメです Warning (Warning)
Breaking the rules is not allowed, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり (きり)
The explanation will only be given once (once)
聞き逃せばあの世行き！
Miss it and you're going to the afterlife!
冗談です♡
Just kidding!♡
(いち！) お菓子を持って
(One!) Grab some sweets!
(に！) 仮装して盛って！
(Two!) Dress up and turn it up!
(さん！) 生者か死者かは隠す事！
(Three!) Keep whether you're living or dead a secret!
(よん！) いつだって笑顔で
(Four!) Always keep a smile!
(ご！) 油断禁物で
(Five!) Never let your guard down!
最後の最後はご無事で帰る事♡
And at the very end, return home safely!♡
独りきりじゃ つまらないわ
Being all alone is so boring.
この退屈な王城の玉座で
On the throne of this boring royal castle,
指折りずっと待ちわびてた
I've been counting down the days waiting.
人恋しいとか？
Am I lonely, you ask?
ヤダ！
No way!
そんなんじゃないってば！
It's nothing like that!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night! !
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrillingly delightful irony!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, it's showtime for the crazy feast!
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How frightening,
(Pa Pa Pa) うらめしや
(Pa Pa Pa) how vengeful.
昔々 憂ささえも忘れてる
Everyone, even forgetting their troubles from long ago,
あらら？
Oh my?
(Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) What a delicious-looking
(Pa Pa Pa) 魂だ！
(Pa Pa Pa) soul!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come on, let's dance!
This is Halloween Night!
響く楽団の Tuning (Tuning)
The orchestra's tuning echoes (Tuning)
その不協和音さえも Music (Music)
Even that dissonance becomes music (Music)
王室のドアが開き (開き)
The royal doors swing open (Open)
拍手喝采が起こる
A thunderous applause erupts!
快感です♡
It feels so good!♡
(いち！) ロウソクを撒いて
(One!) Scatter the candles!
(に！) ドレス纏って
(Two!) Put on your dress!
(さん！) 女王の私のお出ましです！
(Three!) Here comes me, the Queen!
(よん！) 手を取り合って
(Four!) Join hands together!
(ご！) 今日は無礼講で
(Five!) Today, anything goes!
私に魅せられちゃったら最期です♡
If you fall under my spell, it's the end for you!♡
鮮やかなステップ くるり舞ってワルツ
Brilliant steps, twirling in a waltz,
百鬼夜行のリズムに揺られて
Swaying to the rhythm of the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons.
この楽しさ 癖になるわ
This fun is becoming addictive!
時間切れとか...
Time's up, you say...?
ヤダ！
No way!
全然足りないってば！
That's not nearly enough time!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night! !
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!!
Dancing! Dancing! 一夜の怪奇なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! A bizarre memory for one night!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! おもむろに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Stuffed with candies casually!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ あぁ、もっと頂戴！
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, ah, give me more!
泡沫の夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
A fleeting dream dissolving in the faint mist,
蒼白い頬を 涙が伝った
tears ran down pale cheeks.
この姿は誰の為？ 自問自答の末
Who is this appearance for? After asking myself,
禁断の箱開けたら
if I open the forbidden box...
時間を戻す
I'll turn back time...
魔法
Should I use...
使っちゃおうかな！
magic to do it?!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrillingly delightful irony!
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-ta-ta, rat-ta-ta, it's showtime for the crazy feast!
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How frightening,
(Pa Pa Pa) うらめしや
(Pa Pa Pa) how vengeful.
昔々 憂ささえも忘れてる
Everyone, even forgetting their troubles from long ago,
あらら？
Oh my?
(Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) What a delicious-looking
(Pa Pa Pa) 魂だ！
(Pa Pa Pa) soul!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come on, let's dance!
This is Halloween Night!
ハロウィンパーティー いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻ってこられていますか？
Were you able to make it back to our kingdom safely?
冥界の女王様に気に入られてしまうと 魂を奪われてしまって帰ってこられませんからね
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you, she'll steal your soul and you won't be able to return, you know.
戻ってこられて ラッキーでした...なんて ふふっ
You were lucky to make it back... Just kidding. Heheh.
あ 今日のお話はどうでしたか？ 楽しかったでしょうか？
Ah, how were today's stories? Did you enjoy them?
私特にお気に入りは 探偵のお話でして
My personal favorite was the detective story.
今回お聞かせできて とっても嬉しかったです
I was so glad I could share it with you today.
そうだ いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね
Oh, right. Please tell me your story someday too, okay?
もしかすると あの本にあなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ？
Who knows, your story might even be written in that book too.
何と言っても 摩訶不思議な本ですから
After all, it is a truly mysterious book.
何が起こるか 司書である私にも分かりません
Even I, as the librarian, don't know what might happen.
さて そろそろお時間ですね
Well then, it's almost time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら いつでもこの王国図書館へお越しください
If you ever want to hear more stories, please visit this Royal Library anytime.
それでは さようなら
Well then... goodbye.
ハジマリはきっと ひとつの願い それを抱いて わたしは生まれた
The beginning was surely a single wish; holding onto it, I was born.
孤独な夜空 震える指で 点と点を繋げよう
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers, let's connect the dots.
Shirakami Fubuki 1st Solo Live FBKINGDOM ANTHEM
[Title: Shirakami Fubuki 1st Solo Live FBKINGDOM ANTHEM]
LIVE Blu-ray 発売決定！
[Text: LIVE Blu-ray Release Confirmed!]
すこん部の皆さん！ 準備はできてますかー？！
Sukonbu, everyone! Are you ready?!
せーので行きますよー！
Here we go on three!
Say! ほら顔を上げて みんなで手を叩けば
Say! Look up, and if we all clap our hands together,
Say! まだまだ道の途中 世界を超えよう
Say! We're still mid-journey, let me cross the world!
Say! ほら推し押し勝手な 止まらない 全力レースだから
Say! It's an unstoppable, full-speed race for our favorites,
夢を書き換えたら 追いかけ続けよう
So once we rewrite our dreams, let me keep chasing them!
共になれ ファンファーレ GO!
Join together, Fanfare, GO!
だから君がいつか 自分自身の
So if someday you lose sight...
輝きを見失ったときには 思い出してね
...of your own brilliance, please remember...
僕らの星座は 君がいるから 輝く
...our constellation shines because you are here.
Oh Yeah! 眩しい星の中
Oh Yeah! Amidst the dazzling stars,
Oh Yeah! 光を君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me light.
Oh Yeah! もっと越えて行けるさ
Oh Yeah! We can go even further.
Oh Yeah! スーパーノヴァを起こせ今
Oh Yeah! Cause a supernova right now!
Oh Yeah! 何度だって飛べる
Oh Yeah! We can fly time and time again.
これは紛れもなく 僕らの奇跡 High Friends!
This is unmistakably our miracle, High Friends!
ベストフレンド！ すこん部ー！
Best Friends! Sukonbu~!